<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Disco Knight</name>
        <description>A new Homebrew Archetype for the Fighter class, available at 3rd level, the Disco Knight focuses on moving aroud the battle field, building a combo from unarmed attacks to deal devistating blows.
        </description>

        <update version="0.4.5">
            <file name="Fighter-DiscoKnight.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Archy0202/B-Homebrew/main/Fighter-DiscoKnight.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Disco Knight" type="Archetype" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_DiscoKnight">
        <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
        
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <div element="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_Proficiency" />
            <div element="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_BLUNT" />
            <div element="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_BEAT" />
            <div element="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_THROWDOWN" />
            <div element="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_PUNISH" />
            <div element="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_DANCEFLOOR" />
            <div element="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_CAPTIVATED" />
            <div element="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_PANIC" />

        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_Proficiency" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_BLUNT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_BEAT" level="3" />

            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_THROWDOWN" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_PUNISH" level="7" />

            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_DANCEFLOOR" level="10" />

            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_CAPTIVATED" level="15" />
            <!--Improved Combo text update-->
            
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_PANIC" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Additonal Proficiency" type="Archetype Feature" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_Proficiency">
        <description>
            <p>On picking the Disco Knight Archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the performance skill. If you already have proficiency in the skill you add double the modifier to performance checks.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false"/>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERFORMANCE" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Blunt Brawler" type="Archetype Feature" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BluntBrawler">
        <description>
            <p>This feature gives the same benefits as the "Unarmed Fighting" fighting style and an additional bonus.</p>
            <p class="indent"> Your Unarmed Strikes deal Bludgoening damage equal to 1d6 + your strenght modifier on a hit. If your not wielding weapons or a shield the d6 becomes a d8. </p>
            <p> Additionally, from 6th level, your Unarmed Strikes are considered magical if you have an active combo. This is to overcome resistance and immunity to non-magical weapons and attacks. </p>

        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description level="3">
            <p> Your unarmed Strikes deal 1d6 + strenght modifier Bludgoening damage. </p>
            <p class="indent"> The d6 becomes a d8 if you arent wielding weapons or a shield. </p>
            </description>

            <description level="6">
            <p> Your unarmed Strikes deal 1d6 + strenght modifier Bludgoening damage. </p>
            <p class="indent"> The d6 becomes a d8 if you arent wielding weapons or a shield. </p>
            <p> Your Unarmed Strikes are considered Magical if you have an active combo to overcome resistance and immunity.</p>
             </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="To the Beat" type="Archetype Feature" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TheBeat">
        <description>
            <p>Starting from 3rd level, you gain a Disco Beat. It's a special rythm only you can hear that drives you during combat.</p>
            <h4>Follow the Beat</h4>
            <p> At the start of Combat, you designate an enemy that becomes your Target. On your turn, if you attack the "target" and manage to hit an unarmed strike you start a Combo </p>
            <p class="indent">Combo builds for each successful unarmed strike you make against the target up to a value equal to your performance modifier</p>
            <p>At the end of your turn, the creature that is your "target" chnages, you pick another crature within 15ft of you and they become the next target. As long as you attack a creature that is the "target" you continue to maintain and build combo. if you attack an creature that isnt the target your combo breaks and drops to zero.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the creature that is your target dies, on the start of your next turn you designate another creature as the new target. </p>

        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Blunt Brawler" type="Archetype Feature" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_BLUNT">
        <description>
            <p>(Gives the same benefits as Unared Brawler)</p>
            <p>Your unarmed strikes deal Bludgoening damage equal to 1d6 + your strenght modifier on a hit.</p>
            <p class="indent"> If your not wielding weapons or a shield the d6 becomes a d8.</p>
            <p></p>
            <p>Magic Fists.</p>
            <p>Starting from 6th level and onward, your unarmed strikes are considered magical if you have an active combo. this is to overcome resistance and immunity to non-magical attacks and weapons.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description level="3">your unarmed strikes deal 1d6 + your strenght modifier in Bludgoening damage. 1d8 if not weapons or a shield.</description>
            <description level="6">your unarmed strikes deal 1d6 + your strenght modifier in magical Bludgoening damage. 1d8 if not weapons or a shield.</description>
            
        </sheet>
    </element>


    <element name="To the Beat" type="Archetype Feature" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_BEAT">
        <description>
            <p> Starting from 3rd level you gain a disco beat. A special rythm only you can hear that drives you during combat. </p>
            <p>if you follow the beat and its rules you build combo, ehich leads to other effects.</p>
            
            <h5>Following the Beat</h5>
            <p>At the start of Combat, you designate an enemy that becomes your Target.</p>
            <p>On your turn, if you attack the "Target" and manage to hit with an unarmed strike you start a combo. Combo builds for each successful unarmed strike you make against the "Target" up to a value equal to your performance modifier. </p>
            <p class="indent"> At the end of your turn, the creature that is the "Target" changes; you pick another creature within 15ft of you and they become the next target. </p>

            <h5>Spending Combo</h5>
            <p>When you have a combo going, as part of an attack you can do a Finisher; a stronger punch were you pend the combo you have built up.</p>
            <p>As part of an unarmed strike and before you know the resualt of the attack roll, you can decide to add the value of your combo to the attacks damage roll.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a hit, your combo is spent and resets to zero. If you miss the attack, your combo is Halved.</p> 

            <h5>At 10th level</h5>
            <p> From 10th level tyhe feature around combos are improved.</p>
            <li>On your first turn of combat, you can spend your action to gain an initial amount of combo equal to your Charisma modifier.</li>
            <li>The target reselect range is increased to 25ft.</li>

        </description>
        <sheet>

            <description level="3"> At the start of Combat designate a Target, on your turn, each successful unarmed stirke against the Target builds combo up to an amount equal to your performance modifier. 
            At the end of each of your turns, you designate another creature within 15ft as the new target. 
            Combo can be spent on a Finisher.
            A special unarmed strike were, before you know the resualt, decide to spend your active combo and add it to the attacks damage roll. On a miss your combo is halved instead of fully spent.
            </description>

            <description level="10">
            At the start of Combat you designate a Target, on your turn, each successful unarmed stirke against the Target builds combo up to an amount equal to your performance modifier. 
            On your first turn of combat, you can spend your bonus action to gain an initial amount of combo equal to your Charisma modifier.
            At the end of each of your turns, you designate another creature within 25ft as the new target. 
            Combo can be spent on a Finisher.
            A special unarmed strike were, before you know the resualt, decide to spend your active combo and add it to the attacks damage roll. On a miss your combo is halved instead of fully spent.
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Funky Throwdown" type="Archetype Feature" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_THROWDOWN">
        <description>
            <p>Starting from 7th level, when you have a Combo, you can use an attack action to make a grapple check against a creature with a performance check.
            If you succeed the grapple, you drag the creature into your "dance" and can move with them without the "reduced movement" penalty.</p>

            <p>Additionally, when you perform a Finisher and have agrappled creature you can decide to throw the creature instead. </p>
            <p class="indent">you toss the creature up to 15ft; if the thrown creature hit another creature, the other creature needs to succeed a DC14 strenght saving throw or be knock prone. </p>
            <p> If the thrown creature hits an object or creature it takes [2d8 + your strenght modifier + Combo value] in Bludgoening damage and falls prone. </p>
        
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description usage="Attack action"> When you have a Combo, make a grapple check against a creature using your performance. 
            Creatures grappled this way dont impeed movement and can be throw as a Finisher.
            Thrown creatures fly 15ft, taking 2d8 + Str Mod + combo in Bludgoening damage and fall prone. if thrown at another creature they need to make a dc14 str save or fall prone as well. 
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Punisher" type="Archetype Feature" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_PUNISH">
        <description>
            <p>From 7th level, when you get attacked by a creature, you can spend you reaction to change the attacking creature into the combo target. Additionally, as part of this Target change, you get advantage on the next attack roll you make against them. </p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feture a number of times equal to you Profoiciency modifier and regain all uses after a long rest. </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description action="Reaction" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest"> Change the current Target to a creature that spends its action attacking you, on your next turn you gain advantage on the first attack roll made against them.
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Disco Dancefloor" type="Archetype Feature" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_DANCEFLOOR">
        <description>
            <p>Starting from 10th level, you can manifest the groove and beat of disco into battle</p>
            <p> As an action, you can manifest a 25x25ft sqaure around you onto the battlefield; its covered in a vareity of lights and plays a funky tune to anyone in its space.</p>
            <p class="indent"> It remains active for 1min, disapearing afterwards. You can use this ability an amount of times equal to uour Charisma modifier, and regain all uses after a long rest.</p>
            <li>Any creature standing on the dancefloor is a valid target for combo's.</li>
            <li>If an ally is standing on the dance floor and succeeds an attack roll against a creature that is also on the dancefloor, the hit counts to your Combo.</li>
            <li>When doing a Finisher on the dancefloor, if you miss the attack you only lose 1/4th of your combo instead of half</li>

        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description action="Action" usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long rest" level="10" > Manifest a 25x25ft square space around you, any creature In the space counts as a valid combo target.
            Ally attacks within the space count to your combo; and missing a finisher punch while in the space only loses you 1/4th of you combo instead of half.
            </description>

            <description action="Action" usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long rest" level="18"> Manifest a 35x35ft square space around you, any creature In the space counts as a valid combo target.
            Starting your turn on the Dancefloor automatically gives you an amount of combo equal to your charisma modifier.
            successful Ally attacks within the space count to your combo; and you no longer lose combo if you miss a finisher punch while in the space. 
            </description>

        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Captivated Audience" type="Archetype Feature" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_CAPTIVATED">
        <description>
            <p>Starting from 15th level, you can really draw your target into the motions of dance and disco.</p>
            <p>On your turn, as a bonus action, you can force Combo targets (including Dancefloor targets) to make a DC14 wisdom saving throw or become charmed by you.</p>
            <p>Effected creatures will spend their turn dancing and get to remake the Save at the end of their turn.</p>
            <p>A successful saving throw makes the create immune to the effect for 1h.</p>
            <p class="indent">As part of this action, regardless if the target succeds the save ot not, you select a new combo target.</p> 

        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description action="Bonus action">
            Force Combo targets (including dancefloor) to make a Dc14 wisdom Saving Throw or become Charmed by you.
            Charmed creature will spend their turns dancing and get to remake the save and the end of their turn, becoming immune to the effect for 1h on a success.
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Panic at the Disco" type="Archetype Feature" source="B's Homebrew" id="ID_BBrew_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DISCO_PANIC">
        <description>
            <p> Starting from 18th level, your Dancefloor grows and gains additional features. </p>
            <li>The size of the Dancefloor is increaded to a 35x35ft square.</li>
            <li>If you start your turn on the Dancefloor, you automatically gain an amount of Combo equal to your Charisma Modifier.</li>
            <li>You dont lose any combo when missing a finisher attack while on the dancefloor.</li>

            <h5>Special Action</h5>
            <p>When you have an Active Dancefloor, on your turn as an action, you can blow it up.</p>
            <p>Targeting everything standig on the dancefloor, you deal an amount of force damage equal to 2x your active combo as the whole thing goes up in a flash and shatters.</p>
            <p>The dancefloor and all its effects end instantly on detonation</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description usage="Action">
            You Blow an active dancefloor skyhigh, Any creature within its area takes force damage equal to 2x your active combo.
            The Dancefloor is destroyed and all its effects end and you expend all yout current combo.
            </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>